Hello programmer, welcome back to to this another new tutorial session. So today I'll create for
MySQL tutorial series for creating the table in the MySQL. It's a fundamental step in designing
a database schema. Okay, so first of all simply just define create table statement with the MySQL
and here in the MySQL is to create the new table it allows to define the structure of the
database by specifying the column and the other data type. Okay, so here first of all I can just
go and create for the new table. Okay, so here I can just type create and go for here and now
I can just type this is create table and there is for the table name suppose the
employee. Okay, so empl for YS good deploys and parenthesis and here in this inside I can create
for the column information. Okay, so first of all I can create for the ID is the integer, this is the
primary name. Okay next step here I can define for the first name. Okay, so the first name is backward
and define for the text size is 50. Okay, and the next step here I can create this last name
and now here is the barcode then
define the text size is 50. So next step here I can create another column so now define for this
image. Okay, so define for the image or the email for both the barcode and then insert for again
the 100. Okay, and also here I create this higher date. Okay, so define for simply
the style the in the higher date. Okay, so define perfectly and here is simply I'll create
create the statements to create a new table name for the employees and they are defining
for the columns for the employees ID first name last name and the email and the
date and is the ID to set the primary key and ensuring that the record data has
unified. So now just select all the data queries and I'm going to set it now and you can see
here the perfectly created comment is completely successful. Okay, and I hope you perfect understand
and next step here I can create for another table and now just open another new query
and here I can create for another table. So suppose like I can create this statement
for the table's name suppose like the products. Okay, so create for the products table and
in this inside I'll create for the documents for the column document. So first of all I can create
here the ID to this integer and it will create you can choose for the auto implement primary key
but now definitely I can simply describe this ID point is your this will be one key. Okay,
and next step here I'll define the name. Okay, so name is the character
then size is 50. Okay, and also here I can create the price column.
So the price this will be decimal type and here I can create this inside
for 10 and 2. Okay, and also here I can use the
another form and use the start the stock quantity and stock underscore quantity. So the stock
quantity this is the integer. Okay, so now here the second table with the
table here for the product and add for the price column ensuring it's a
default and I can create for the stock quantity column and this has to help for maintaining the
data and prevent for this completely pure data table. So first of all here I can select and execute.
So now just do it and you can see here this form and completely successful. Okay,
so now just verify this table and first of all go here and just type over here you can see
the another way. So just put your and select for this is the cells on the database
and create okay. So not create this is the select start from suppose first of all where create
the table okay. So define the employee's table and now just select an execute and you can see here
and completely creating this column. So here previously field the five columns so field the first
idea and the last name and the unit and the high table. Next step here I create another table which
I'll show you the various tables name as the product table okay. So now select and execute
and you'll see here perfectly created the column so ID name price structure quantity.
So here this is completely done and here I can perfectly overview and create the table in the
MySQL which is a practical example. So I hope you perfectly find this tutorial helpful.
So now stay tuned for more MySQL tips and picks. So thank you for watching.